Yesterday, the world got its first look
at the most innovative, most exciting,
and most dystopian tech product of 2025.
The $799 Ray-B band sunglasses that lets
you live life like a fighter pilot with
a full color heads-up display. And not
only that, but it can practically read
your mind thanks to this thing called
the Meta Neural Band, which is a
bracelet that measures movement before
it's even visually perceptible. A
product this terrifying could only be
conceived by one man, Mark Zuckerberg,
who demoed them at Metacon Connect 2025.
The presentation was truly impressive at
times, but not everything went according
to plan. Actually, that's an
understatement. This could go down in
history as one of the biggest live demo
fails since Elon tried to demo the
bulletproof glass of the Cybert truck.
Oh my god. Well, maybe that was
a little too hard.
In today's video, we'll look at the
incredible tech behind Meta's new
halfbaked Ray-B bands and find out what
it'll be like to interact with fellow
humans in the future. It is September
18th, 2025, and you're watching the Code
Report. When Meta released its AI smart
glasses last year, the first thing
people did was develop an app to dox
people in real time by connecting its
real-time video feed to facial
recognition software. This has allowed
men to optimize the way they talk to
women by knowing all their personal
details in advance. That's awesome. But
these new Meta Rayband display glasses
represent a breakthrough in three key
areas. First, it has a fullcolor
highresolution 600x600 pixel display
positioned in the right lens. The
display is translucent and doesn't
obstruct the wearer's natural vision.
That means when your parents call you in
for an important conversation to get a
job and move out of their basement, you
can maintain eye contact while still
getting all of your important Instagram
notifications. The second innovation in
these new Ray-B bands is just the sheer
amount of AI slot packed into the
device. They're much bulkier than
regular WFarers, but have a 6-hour
battery life and allow you to do things
like translate conversations in real
time to any language. They can recognize
images in the real world and also
respond with new images generated by AI.
One real world use case for this feature
is that it could turn any modern wife
into a trad wife by leveling up her
cooking skills. At Meta Connect, they
attempted to live demo cooking, but it
failed hard.
What do I do first?
You've already combined the base
ingredients, so now grate a pair to add
to the sauce.
What do I do first?
You've already combined the base
ingredients, so now grate the pear and
gently combine it with the base sauce.
All right, I think the Wi-Fi might be
messed up. Sorry. Back to you, Mark.
It's all good. You know what?
It's all good.
They tried to play it off as a Wi-Fi
problem, but clearly the problem is that
the AI here just isn't very intelligent.
The third and most impressive
innovation, though, is the Meta Neural
Band. A wristband that comes with every
pair of display glasses. It uses
electromyiography technology to sense
tiny electrical signals in your wrist
that correspond to the way you move your
hands. This thing can actually detect
how your hands are going to move before
the movement even happens. It completely
replaces old-fashioned touchcreens on
antique devices like the iPhone because
everything can now be controlled with
subtle finger movements. What's most
impressive is that it works universally
on all humans without calibration. The
only exception being humans with no
arms. That amazing feat was achieved by
testing it on over 200,000 participants.
But is this approach actually intuitive
from a UIUX perspective?
I don't know about you. When I watch TV,
we had a I accidentally exited. That's
my fault. That's my fault.
It's all good.
Okay, we're good now.
It's really live.
As you can see, even Meta employees seem
to struggle using it. But despite these
live demo failures, you have to give
Meta some credit for having the balls to
demo it live. It's a refreshing change
from the over glamorous Apple style
announcements, but Meta probably could
have shipped a more stable product if
they ran their CI/CD pipelines with
Blacksmith, the sponsor of today's
video. It's a drop in replacement for
GitHub runners that lets you run your
GitHub actions twice as fast while
costing 75% less. That might sound too
good to be true, but they're able to
achieve this blazing speed by running
your actions on bare metal gaming CPUs
with the highest single core
performance. Blacksmith also makes your
GitHub actions fully observable, so you
can quickly see what's happening in your
CI pipeline when something goes wrong,
which is critical when you have agents
writing thousands of lines of code with
no parental supervision. Try Blacksmith
for free today at the link below, and
you'll get 3,000 free minutes per month
when you sign up. This has been the Code
Report. Thanks for watching, and I will
see you in the next one.
[Music]